Vandish Gandhi

+61 450602494 vandish009@hotmail.com

Profile

Vandish is a frontend developer who is strongly focused on frontend technologies and JavaScript ranging React, Angular, JQuery, backbone.js, knockout.js and vanilla JavaScript. He is a self-motivated developer having commercial experience of more than 5 years, with proven track record for on time delivery of projects. He's ICAgile certified for agile fundamental practices and a team player ranging from his primary specialization on the front-end to API engineering and infrastructure setup for cross platform apps.

Education

Master of Business (Information Systems & ERP) – Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia (2013)

Achievements: Distinction in Business Intelligence, ABAP, Management of IT, CRM.

Bachelor of Computer Application – Gujarat University, India (2011)

Relevant Subjects: Database Management, Information Technology & Programming, Programming in

C, Object Oriented Programming with C++.

Achievements: Distinction in Object Oriented Programming in C++, Programming in C.

Technical Skills

Analytics : Adobe Analytics, New Relic

Java scripting Framework : React, Angular, Ember, Vanilla js, jQuery, backbone

Web Designing : HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS, SaaS and Less

Automated Testing : Selinium, Jasmine, Karma, Chai, Mocha (Expert)

Reporting Tools : Omniture, Power BI

Operating System : Win NT, XP, 7, 8, Mac OSx,Linux,CentOS
Office Tools : Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access (Expert)
Computer Programming : C, C++, Bash Scripting (Linux), COBOL,Pascal

Server Side Programming : ASP.Net,PHP,ASP.Net MVC, Python,C#,VBA(Event driven)

Source Client Side Scripting : ¡Query, Ajax, JavaScript, VBScript

Data Formats : XML, JSON

ERP System : SAP

Project Management tool : Microsoft Project, Altassian Jira

Content Mgt. System : WordPress, Joomla, Drupal, Altassian Confluence

Web Services : REST, SOAP (Working Knowledge)

RDBMS : MYSQL, MS SQL, Oracle Database (Intermediate Skills)

NoSQL : Mongo DB

Source Control Systems : GIT, Github, Sourcetree (GUI), Github GUI

Web server Framework : Apache Xampp, IIS, Hadoop (conceptual understanding)

Industry Experience

Frontend Lead for Adslot (November 2018 – Present)

Responsible for:

- Contributing to front-end decision-making and architecture
- Maintaining team focus on reusable code, patterns and libraries
- Optimising application for maximum performance, maintainability and Scalability
- Maintaining open-source UI pattern libraries in React
- Collaborating and communicate with Front-End/Full-Stack Developers and stakeholders
- Mentoring, training and organising other Developers
- Conducting thorough and constructive code-reviews and unit-tests

Application Stack:

Front end: React with Redux and Context API, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Angular JS & Coffee Script.

Project Management Tools: Altassian Jira, Confluence & Microsoft Sharepoint.

Source Control: Github, Jenkins (CI)

Senior Frontend Consultant for DWS (August 2017 – November 2018)

Client: Telstra

Project: Prepaid Activation (https://telstra.com.au/prepaidactivation)

Responsible for:

- Leading and maintaining frontend application for prepaid activation.
- Using agile/lean for software development, including TDD/BDD, pairing, and continuous integration.
- Driving the UX to make sure the application is responsive on web development, cross-browser and platform agnostic.
- Mentoring offshore developers in React development and ensure smooth bi-weekly development cycle with efficient source control management.
- Analysing business requirements to propose software design approach

Application Stack:

Front end: React with Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Less, Bootstrap, JQuery and DOM api.

Project Management Tools: Altassian Jira, Confluence & Microsoft Sharepoint

Source Control: Altassian Sourcetree/Bitbucket, Git

Frontend Developer for ERM Power Ltd. (June 2016 – August 2017)

Project: Customer Portal (https://myportal.ermpower.com.au)

Responsible for:

- Developing user interface and engineering user experience for customer portal built on EmberJS
- Formulating & standardizing the ERM look and feel across internal and external projects
- Analysing business requirements to propose software design approach
- Driving the customer facing look and feel of ERM Web user interfaces
- Designing collateral mock ups for marketing and business units;
- Providing guidance for user experience and system implementation.

Application Stack:

Front end: Ember.js, HTML5, CSS3, Saas, Bootstrap

Backend: ASP.NET MVC, C#

Software Developer for University of Technology (June 2015 – June 2016) Project: Farm management dashboard

Responsible for:

- Developing, maintaining and cross platform testing frontend application build on Angular 1.5.
- Integrating Bootstrap, Angular Material and Foundation frameworks to enhance look and feel of web application as required.
- Maintaining instances on AWS, code deployment and load balancing on servers for incoming traffic.

Software Developer for Bombardier Transportation (June 2014- June 2015) Project: QNGR (Queensland New Generation Rolling stock)

Responsible for:

- Full Stack development using MVC architecture in PHP, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax and jQuery using MySQL as backend database.
- Developing project plans, schedule, budget and risk assessment.

Programming Intern for Cosmic Infocom, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India (2010-2011) *Responsible for:*

- Coding firmware to communicate with PRI interface for call conferencing purposes.
- Designing web application using Microsoft Visual studio in ASP.NET.
- Building database for the client and integrating with web application using MS SQL.

Non-technical Skills

- Excellent oral and written communication skills from various roles and leasing with businesses.
- Proven organisational and time management skills as sole programmer in Bombardier and UTS.
- Developed skill to multi-task and work under demanding conditions from multiple projects.
- Gained an expert skill base in Microsoft Office applications from coursework and industry experience

Certification

- ICAgile. Certification: Agile professional
- Authority: Australian Computer society. Certification: Analyst Programmer.
- Authority: SAP University Alliance & Victoria University. Certificate of achievement for:
 - Business Intelligence systems
 - Advanced Business Application Programming(ABAP)

Hobbies and Interest

Photography, snooker and travelling.